<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<leader xmlns="http://marklogic.com/mlu/world-leaders">
    <!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
        granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
        GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
        the Free Software Foundation. Content derived from 
        http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/David_Cameron.      
        Modified in August 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
        GNU Free Documentation License.-->
    <name>
        <firstname>David</firstname>
        <lastname>Cameron</lastname>
    </name>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <dob location="United Kingdom">1966-10-09</dob>
    <gender>male</gender>
    <positions>
        <position hog="true">
            <title>Prime Minister</title>
            <startdate>2010-05-11</startdate>
            <enddate>present</enddate>
        </position>
        <position>
            <title>Leader of the Opposition</title>
            <startdate>2005-12-06</startdate>
            <enddate>2005-12-06</enddate>
        </position>       
        <position>
            <title>Shadow Secretary of State for Education and Skills</title>
            <startdate>2005-12-06</startdate>
            <enddate>2005-12-06</enddate>
        </position> 
    </positions>
    <summary>
        David William Donald Cameron is the current Prime Minister of the United Kingdom, First Lord of the Treasury, and <b>Leader of the Conservative Party</b>. He is the Member of Parliament (MP) for Witney.         
        Cameron studied Philosophy, Politics and Economics at Oxford, gaining a first class honours degree. He then joined the Conservative Research Department and became Special Adviser to Norman Lamont, and then to Michael Howard. He was Director of Corporate Affairs at Carlton Communications for seven years. 
        A first candidacy for Parliament at Stafford in 1997 ended in defeat, but Cameron was elected in 2001 as the Member of Parliament for the Oxfordshire constituency of Witney. He was promoted to the Opposition front bench two years later, and rose rapidly to become head of policy co-ordination during the 2005 general election campaign. With a public image of a young, moderate candidate who would appeal to young voters, he won the Conservative leadership election in 2005.[1]
        In the 2010 general election held on 6 May, the Conservatives gained a plurality of seats in a hung parliament and Cameron was appointed Prime Minister on 11 May 2010, at the head of a coalition between the Conservatives and the Liberal Democrats. At the age of 43, Cameron became the youngest British Prime Minister since the Earl of Liverpool 198 years earlier.[2] The Cameron Ministry is the first coalition government in the United Kingdom since the Second World War.
    </summary>
</leader>