<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<leader xmlns="http://marklogic.com/mlu/world-leaders">
    <!--Copyright (c) 2010 Mark Logic Corporation. Permission is
        granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this document under the terms of the
        GNU Free Documentation License, Version 1.2 or any later version published by
        the Free Software Foundation. Content derived from 
        http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gordon_Brown.      
        Modified in August 2010 by Mark Logic Corporation under the terms of the 
        GNU Free Documentation License.-->
    <name>
        <firstname>Gordon</firstname>
        <lastname>Brown</lastname>
    </name>
    <country>United Kingdom</country>
    <dob location="United Kingdom">1951-02-20</dob>
    <gender>male</gender>
    <positions>
        <position hog="true">
            <title>Prime Minister</title>
            <startdate>2007-06-27</startdate>
            <enddate>2010-05-11</enddate>
        </position>
        <position>
            <title>Chancellor of the Exchequer</title>
            <startdate>1997-05-02</startdate>
            <enddate>2007-06-27</enddate>
        </position>
    </positions>
    <summary>
        James Gordon Brown is a British Labour Party politician, who has been a Member of Parliament (MP) since 1983, currently for Kirkcaldy and Cowdenbeath. He served as the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom and Leader of the Labour Party from 2007 until 2010. Brown became Prime Minister in June 2007, after the resignation of Tony Blair and three days after becoming leader of the governing Labour Party. Immediately before this, he had served as Chancellor of the Exchequer in the Labour Government from 1997 to 2007. His tenure ended in May 2010, when he resigned as Prime Minister and Leader of the Labour Party.
        Brown has a PhD in History from the University of Edinburgh and spent his early career working as a television journalist. He has been a Member of Parliament since 1983; first for Dunfermline East and since 2005 for Kirkcaldy and Cowdenbeath. As Prime Minister, he also held the offices of First Lord of the Treasury and the Minister for the Civil Service.
        Brown's time as Chancellor was marked by major reform of Britain's monetary and fiscal policy architecture, transferring interest rate setting powers to the Bank of England, by a wide extension of the powers of the Treasury to cover much domestic policy and by transferring responsibility for banking supervision to the Financial Services Authority. Controversial moves included the abolition of advance corporation tax (ACT) relief in his first budget, and the removal in his final budget of the 10% "starting rate" of personal income tax which he had introduced in 1999.
    </summary>
</leader>